Uriel Knopf

UrielKnopf@gmail.com | (570) 350-0115 | Linkedin: <u>@uknopf</u> |Github: <u>@urieknopf</u> Allentown, PA - Open to relocation and remote

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience with web-based applications. Experienced in designing and implementing file ingestion and data management systems, Frontend designs, and UI/UX interfaces. Focused on improving app functionality and documentation. Seeking Full Stack or Backend roles where I can enhance user experience.

SKILLS

- Python | C++ | Javascript | Linux / BASH | SQL | HTML5 | CSS3
- AWS Amplify and AWS Cloudformation
- Docker and Containerization
- Jira and Agile methodologies
- Technical writing and documentation

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Rootnote.co | June 2022 - September 2022

- Developed a web-based application focused on data collection and analysis for users.
 - Application based on AWS with Amplify Studio integration. Front end based on Javascript React and Next.js. The back end primarily consisted of Python and Lambda functions. The database consisted of MongoDB with GraphQL.
- Designed and developed file ingestion and ETL system for the application.
- Coordinate and develop app and company direction during company-wide meetings.
- Advise on and implement security and good programming practices.
- Automate repetitive operations processes as needed and maintain app security.

Software Engineer | Obscurity Labs | May 2021 - May 2022

- Developed, modified, implemented, and delivered high-quality code to maintain the application and meet contract requirements.
 - Application based on Django/python with React. Multiple remote EC2
 Centos-based instances integrated with RabbitMQ and Postgresql.
 - CI/CD maintained through Jenkins, Ansible, Cloudformation template, and version control through Bitbucket.
- Work closely with operations and security teams to engineer solutions that capture all business requirements and provide impactful solutions with agile development processes and thorough documentation.
- Develop related test data and automate unit testing with npm and PyTest

Technical Support Receptionist | Orchard Software | April 2017 - March 2018

- Assisted technical support in answering clients' questions and resolving problems.
- Managed client tickets and resolutions through Jira ticket portal.
- Delivered exceptional customer support and maintained healthy client relationships.
- Helped improve user experience and call wait times.

Social Media Manager | Doctor Gus | October 2014 - January 2017

- Designed and implemented social media concepts and content.
- Assisted in managing, developing, and implementing media campaigns; improved sales by implementing campaigns.
- Designed, implemented, and updated company websites with relevant information.
- Improved user experience and sales through social media.

Freelance Developer | Freelance | March 2013 - January 2014

- Designed, developed, and implemented customer websites and applications.
- Worked with various technologies, including PHP, SQL, HTML, and CSS.
- Collected and sanitized client data using technologies including MySQL.
- Managed yearly form and data updates for tax-rates.org using manual and automated scraping of public tax form data.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Science | Computer Science | East Stroudsburg University

Organizations

- CSO ARCS Webinars | Founder
 - Accessibility and Representation in Computer Science webinar hosted by the Computer Science Organization at ESU.
- Computer Science Organization | Mentor
 - Tutored and assisted underclassmen through the computer science program at ESU.